Speaker 1: - The left isn't giving up on the Smithsonian. They're preparing to take it back. And we know exactly what they think they're saving. In a resurfaced presentation to UCLA students, National Museum of American History director
Speaker 2: Anthea Hardig proudly laid out her version of history for the museum.
Speaker 3: - I want to take this time to share a number of ways in which your National Museum of American History is taking an equity-based
Speaker 3: justice-forward, community-driven, and necessarily humble approach to public history.
Now
Speaker 4: comes my favorite part. Apparently, history really is not about facts anymore.
Speaker 5: History as a practice is, for me, a prime tool of social
Speaker 3: justice. It's also in a way in which I've grown personally. It continues to grow resolute in my
mind.
And
Speaker 3: it is the key that unlocks the mysteries of humanity, of meaning, of place, of conquest, of love, of power, authority, and
Speaker 1: self." Social justice. You bet. That's the philosophy that President Trump is trying to root out. And that's exactly why the left is panicking.
Now
Speaker 1: that they've got a plan, they've got a budget, they have a volunteer army at the Smithsonian. Hundreds of activists from citizen historians for the Smithsonian have run through the galleries with cell phones, taking more than 50,000 photos and videos. Not saving history to make sure nobody
Speaker 6: edits their restorative version of it.
Speaker 1: One organizer admits it's designed to be a check on the administration.
Speaker 1: But it's not about protecting artifacts. It's about preserving their narrative. It's anti-American. It's deeply, deeply cynical. And it's about restructuring history for a new age. Here to react is Missouri Senator Josh Hawley. Senator, look, they have the media lined up on their side, don't they? We have, you know, most Americans think President Trump shouldn't be involved in museums. They have this survey from YouGov obviously priming the pump here
Speaker 2: that Trump's trying to rewrite history.
Speaker 2: What's really going on at this museum?
- Yeah, I can
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): tell you for sure that
what most
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): Americans think is that their tax money shouldn't go to people who hate America and shouldn't be paying for exhibits about how horrible America is. I listened to that word salad gobbledygook that you just played from the director. I think the translation is real simple. These people hate the United States of America. I can never figure out why liberals hate this country so much.
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): But they now want to use as much tax money as possible to force this anti-American propaganda down our throats. And I think the American people are saying no more. I'm glad President Trump is standing up to these people. And my question is, why does this Smithsonian director still have a job? Why isn't she fired and why
Speaker 8: doesn't she give back every dime of taxpayer money she has taken?
Speaker 1: Well, I want to get to that. So the woman we just heard with the restorative history gobbledygook, Anthea Hardig, OK, she testified before Congress recently. She puts on kind of a very demure kind of presentation, "Oh, I'm not a threat." But only the secretary of the Smithsonian, this guy Lonnie Bunch III, could fire her under the trust that the Smithsonian is organized under.
Speaker 1: Unless the Board of Regents, which includes, you know, the Supreme Court chief justice includes, I believe, J.D. Vance, a few members of Congress, a few people from both parties, some others, unless they step forward and say, we have no confidence in Lonnie Bunch, who's in on the whole, you know, anti-American game here, then she gets to keep her position and continues
Speaker 9: to undermine the objective telling of history.
Yeah, I think
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): it's ridiculous, and maybe it's time for Congress to change that statute. I mean, maybe it's
time to
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): say that if you hate this country, you shouldn't be getting paid with taxpayer money. Maybe it's time to say that we shouldn't be spending Americans' hard-earned cash to tell Americans how terrible their country is. The whole thing is a farce, Laura. It's a scam. It's a scam that the left has used. They've captured all these institutions. Now they want to capture the Smithsonian. Trump is trying to hold them accountable. You know, maybe it's time for Congress to do something about it. I know this for sure, she ought to be gone and every dime of taxpayer
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): money she's been paid. She
Speaker 10: ought to pay back. I
think
Speaker 2: you have a lot more than Anthea Hartig over there. You have mid-level leadership. You have her. You have Lonnie Bunch. I mean, this whole crowd
Speaker 1: has to be replaced by people who just have an objective view of history, but love the country because we want everyone in the world to see how great this country is, flaws and all. Senator, thank you very much. We're going to keep following this.